[MUSIC]
I want to discuss why the Programming
Languages course is actually on Coursera,
three courses Part A, Part B, Part C,
why we made that decision and
how the three pieces fit together.
So the biggest reason we split it into
three parts is because it's a large
course, there's a lot of material.
People who've finished the entire course,
Part A, Part B and Part C,
have spent somewhere between 100 and
200 hours.
It very much depends on the person and
how quickly they go through the material.
And so it just seemed like a lot,
the way most modern courses,
online courses are at this point
to call that all one course.
This is something that corresponds
to something that students in
my university do over a 10 or
11 week period while they're not trying to
do a lot of other things in their lives,
although they are taking a couple
other courses at the same time.
Now splitting it up was not easy for
me to do.
If you can imagine writing a novel and
then having someone say,
I really only want to read
the first few chapters.
That's kind of how I feel
splitting up the course.
It really does all fit together,
there are cross-cutting themes that only
really make sense once you get to the end.
There are neat things that tie together
once you get into Part B and Part C.
There are contrasts that we can't
do until late in the course.
And overall, I've put a lot of thought
into what is in this course and
just as importantly, what is not,
to have it all sort of packaged up as one
piece that tells a consistent
story from beginning to end.
And I cannot emphasize enough how much
I want all of you to participate all
the way through to the end of Part C.
And, indeed, the goal here was not to
split it into three courses that try to
make more money or
make you think you're doing three
times more than you're actually doing.
And usually, when I say the course,
I mean everything.
So what I've done here is basically
argue that I shouldn't have split it up,
but obviously we did, so
let me now explain the reasons why we did.
The biggest one is that there's just more
material and it's more challenging and
you in some sense deserve the credit for
completing three courses worth of material
and the places where we split it
are reasonable intermediate milestones.
They are places where you should feel
very proud of getting that far and
if you choose to go no further,
you will have learned something and
they sort of are reasonable
stopping points that make sense.
So you deserve recognition for that,
it's something that when we had
everything together, as we did when we
first offered this MOOC, we didn't have.
And so I think that's a great
step in a really good direction.
It will also give you a chance
to take a break, if you will.
As you go through Part A,
you really don't want to lose momentum.
You want to do each piece of the course
in sort of consecutive weeks, so
that you can keep track of everything.
But if you wanted to take a couple weeks
off or a month off before starting Part B.
Well, it might be a little tough
to remember where you were and
get started again but, again,
because it's a reasonable stopping point,
I actually think that
makes a lot of sense.
And so it's a way that kind of let
you go through the overall course at
a slower pace by going sort of
at a certain pace for Part A and
then taking a break before
Part B that sort of thing.
So in terms of how it breaks down,
I say unfortunately,
each part of the course is done in
a different programming language.
I say unfortunate because it feeds
back into this idea that the parts of
courses are about the languages where I
keep emphasizing that they're really not.
But nonetheless,
that is how things break down.
I should also emphasize that we
didn't break it into thirds, right?
We picked the reasonable stopping points,
and the way that worked out
is Part B is definitely the biggest
part of the three parts.
And could we divide Part A into two
smaller pieces, maybe we could but
I don't see a natural breaking point,
so I didn't, all right?
So the way this breaks down is that
Part A has three homework assignments and
then a fourth substantial section
that has no homework assignment but
does have an exam, so to finish Part A,
is really four major units of the course.
Then Part B is only two more units, so
about half the size of Part A, although,
the second of those units has what's
usually considered the most challenging,
and also most rewarding
homework in the course.
And then Part C, where we study object
oriented programming and then compare and
contrast it back with the functional
programming that we do in Part A and
Part B, has just another two homeworks but
then a final exam.
And that exam focuses
mostly on Parts B and C.
because you'll notice Part B
doesn't have an exam.
But refers a little bit to contrast with
Part A, because when you get to the end of
the course you'll see that that's
an appropriate thing to do.
So altogether,
things are one course in three parts.
I hope you appreciate that.
It's perhaps obvious, but I'll say it,
that you can't really do Part B without
Part A and you can't really
do Part C without Parts A and
Part B because they often
refer back to earlier parts.
And that's the story of how
we divided things up and
we hope that you make the most
of the material available to you
in the way that makes
the most sense to you.